Clearly, you're quite
an observant young man.
You must look at things
- very carefully.
- [Tartah gasps]
[TARTAH] That mysterious
flash of light...
I wonder how much
he really knows.
[TARTAH] Say, Mr. Qifrey.
You know, since you're here,
I have something to ask you.
Do you?
Wonderful!
[TARTAH] Uh?
[QIFREY] Oh, I simply adore
talking about magic.
I would be more than happy
to answer any questions
you might have!
What would you like to know?
Go on! Tell me!
[Tartah stutters]
[TARTAH] I can't tell him,
it's not that kind of question.
Not with him sparklin'
away like that!
Pardon.
You brought the young lady?
Please, come with me.
[DOCTOR] What we have here
is a cold,
- brought on by exhaustion.
- [Coco breathes heavily]
[Qifrey sighs softly]
[DOCTOR] It's clear she hasn't
been getting enough sleep.
With rest
and some nutritious meals,
her condition should improve.
I'd like to keep her here
overnight, just to be safe.
Thank you, doctor.
[DOCTOR] Honestly,
I don't know the first thing
about what kind of training
you witches
put yourselves through,
- but she's a child.
- [door opens]
The adults in her life
would do well
not to lose sight of that fact.
[door closes]
[Qifrey sighs deeply]
- [TARTAH] Uh?
- Yes, quite so.
I'm sorry, Coco.
[scribbling]
[inhales, blows]
[Tartah gasps softly]
[Coco breathes heavily]
Hopefully, that will at least
ease the fever a bit.
I don't understand.
Why would she work herself
to the point of collapse?
[QIFREY] Our bodies
and minds are remarkable.
But sometimes even their
very best isn't enough.
Until recently,
Coco was entirely ignorant
to the reality of witches.
That cheerful demeanor
of hers...
may hide great insecurity
and fear.
[Tartah gasps softly]
[TARTAH] I had no idea.
The Outsider
I keep hearing about.
Is it possible she...
- [QIFREY] Tartah.
- [TARTAH] Uh?
[QIFREY] About that question
you wanted to ask me,
could we put it off a bit?
This hardly seems the time.
[TARTAH] Right.
I agree with you.
- Some other day then.
- [bell tolling]
[QIFREY] Uh?
[TARTAH] I'd better head home.
Of course. Take care.
- [footsteps]
- [Tartah panting]
[TARTAH] For a moment,
I felt a coldness in his eyes
that chilled me to the bone.
Perhaps I was imagining things.
[GATEKEEPER] Afraid not!
This ferry is exclusively
for witches.
If you live on the island,
then where's your pointed cap?
A PROMISE IN SILVER
Won't be able to let you on
unless I see proof
you're a witch.
It's right here.
Uh...
- What? It's gone!
- [GATEKEEPER] Huh?
[TARTAH] I rode
this morning, I swear...
Is that so? You really think
little brats like you
haven't tried that line
on me before?
[GATEKEEPER] Hey, get back here!
[TARTAH] I can't get home
without my hat.
I have to find it!
[DOCTOR] Her breathing
has settled nicely.
With continued rest,
she'll be well in no time.
Thank goodness.
[DOCTOR] I must say.
The cool atmosphere
you've created in this room
doesn't hurt.
Witches certainly are amazing.
I'd say the same of you doctors.
My abilities
can't make her better,
but yours can.
Come, now.
This will aid in her recovery.
If only we could all make use
of such power.
- [QIFREY] Indeed.
- [running footsteps]
I need a doctor!
The bar to the north is on fire!
We've been trying to help
the injured get out of there,
but they're all drunk, so--
[man gasps]
Are you a witch?
And you use water magic!
That's perfect!
Come with me and help us
put out the fire!
Witches are supposed
to help people in trouble,
- aren't they?
- Please, just wait a moment!
I can't leave!
I need to stay here
with my apprentice!
- [COCO] I'll be all right.
- [both gasp]
Go help those people.
That's what witches
are supposed to do.
Very well. I'll do that.
And you get some rest.
[Coco sighs]
[QIFREY] Right.
Let's be on our way.
[DOCTOR] Thank you, good sir!
[QIFREY]
How serious is the fire?
[MAN] It was still small
when I left,
but now, who knows?
- We need to hurry! Come on!
- [Coco breathes softly]
[COCO] I was trying to be brave,
but the truth is,
I'm terrified to be alone
right now.
- [running footsteps]
- [panting]
[TARTAH] I've searched
everywhere I could think of,
with no luck.
- This is the last place...
- [DOCTOR] Make haste!
Excuse me, coming through.
Please let me find it.
Oh. There you are!
[Tartah sighs]
What a relief.
Now I can get back home.
- [Coco groans softly]
- [TARTAH] Uh?
[TARTAH]
That doesn't sound good.
Coco? How are you feeling?
[gasps softly]
[Coco groans softly]
Tartah?
- Sorry.
- This is a nice surprise.
What are you... [coughs]
[TARTAH] You all right?
That cold only seems
to be getting worse.
Let's see. Where is everyone?
What happened
to all the doctors?
And Mr. Qifrey?
[COCO] A fire broke out.
They all went to help.
[running footsteps]
[TARTAH] That explains
all the commotion.
Wonder how long they'll take
to get back.
Perhaps I'd better
go fetch someone.
- [Coco coughing]
- [TARTAH] Uh?
There must be a way to help.
Oh! I know how we can bring
the fever down!
Remember Tranquileaf?
I used it on your leg.
But it can also help
with fever and coughing.
It must be around here
somewhere.
Ah!
[Tartah gasps softly]
[TARTAH] There are no labels.
What is this?
What kind of hospital leaves
their medicines unlabeled?
What if they got mixed up?
Some of them do seem
darker than others.
Can other people tell which ones
are which by their color?
[Tartah sighs]
The same old story.
People look at the world
around them,
never thinking
others might see it differently.
[WITCH 1] Silverwash, eh?
[WITCH 2] That leaves out
complex spells
with magic dyes, for a start.
[WITCH 1] And it's hard
to see him getting very far
as a magic stationer.
[FEMALE WITCH]
It's not so bad now,
but when he gets older...
[WITCH 3] At least he's good
at carving pens.
[WITCH 1] The fact is,
there are certain things
that certain people
just can't do.
You should concentrate
on the things that you can.
Damn it all.
The components in magic dyes
are often used in medicine.
If I knew what they were,
I'd have an idea
what they can do.
But as it stands, I'm helpless!
In this world,
where everything's
colored silver...
there's not a single path
in sight.
- [Tartah gasps softly]
- [weakly] Tartah...
I'm sorry. You're suffering,
and here I am, pitying myself.
[Coco coughing]
[TARTAH] Uh?
You must be thirsty.
I'll pour you some water.
Here. Drink up.
[Coco exhales]
Thank you, Tartah.
[Tartah gasps softly]
[TARTAH] A Vapor Bubble.
Come to think of it,
I see Granda using
one of these all the time
when he's making ink.
Of course! I could simply
reverse the process!
If I extract the water
from the medicine,
perhaps I can identify
its components!
Tranquileaf's used
in powder form.
They dry it out and crush it.
So a powder's
what I'm looking for!
It's not these crystals.
It's not this stuff that shines
in the moonlight.
This one's still liquid,
so that can't be it.
And Tranquileaf
has no particular odor,
so I can rule out
the ones that smell pungent.
After all that.
There's still three left.
Damn. Damn!
I've come so far,
and now I'm stuck!
I'm...
done.
♪
[water sloshes softly]
[TARTAH] Forgive me, Coco.
I gave it my best,
but this is simply beyond me.
I don't know why I ever
let myself think otherwise.
I knew I couldn't do it.
I knew it right from the start.
[COCO] But you were wrong.
There is a way...
to turn the things
you can't do...
into things you can. Magic.
[Tartah gasps softly]
[COCO] You have ink and a pen?
I do have some ink!
And a pen
that I've been carving.
[Coco exhales softly]
[scribbling]
[Coco shivers]
[TARTAH] Uh?
Are you all right?
[COCO] Mm-hm.
[TARTAH] What kind of spell
are you drawing?
Whatever it is,
will it make you feel better?
[COCO] Mm-mm.
It's not for me.
Not just for me, anyway.
The spell I'm drawing...
is one that's going
to help the both of us.
[Tartah gasps] Really?
A spell that could help me
as well?
What kind of magic is that?
[Coco chuckles softly]
This is the Sigil of Earth.
It's incredible.
It can dig tunnels.
Turn rocks into grains of sand.
And how is it gonna help us now?
Changing signs
changes the spell.
I inverted the Signs of Crushing
from their usual position.
Normally, this spell turns
solid things to powder.
So then
if you inverted the signs,
it would become a spell to turn
powdered things back
into their solid form!
[COCO] Right.
And that's where you come in.
You know what these components
originally looked like.
This spell is for you, Tartah.
It's what will lead you
to the answer.
[COCO] Huh?
[TARTAH] Hm?
[COCO] That was
as big a mess as I am.
All wobbly and uneven.
[TARTAH] In other words,
you need these same shapes
drawn more neatly?
[COCO] And ideally,
more symmetrical.
[TARTAH] I don't really draw,
but I can see
the balance in things.
It's what I do all the time.
[Coco gasps softly]
Say, about this sign here...
Right now, it's just
at the top and bottom,
would it be all right to
add it on the sides, too?
A three-dimensional object
needs to be shaped
from every possible angle.
In its current form,
the spell is likely failing
due to insufficient information.
But if we... [gasps]
Sorry! I shouldn't be
adjusting your spell.
Please, it's fine.
It's just a basic spell.
Besides, if you change a spell
to help it work,
I'd say that makes it
your spell.
[Tartah gasps softly]
Now give it a try.
Hm. I will.
♪
[scribbling]
[Tartah breathes shakily]
Coco...
I did it.
It only lasted for a second.
But I did it!
Well done! [coughs]
[TARTAH] Oh, sorry!
The medicine.
No Tranquileaf.
Good thing we checked,
or this could've ended badly.
I was so certain it had
to be one of them.
Right!
The next step
is to use this spell
to search the storage room.
Now I know I can find
what we need!
[door opens, closes]
[TARTAH]
This reminds me of home.
Thornbark.
Milliflower.
Seabriar.
Sleeping Willow.
Drizzlebee Hive.
I've seen them all,
as drawings in books.
And now here they are,
right in front of me!
Amazing!
When I hold up this seal,
it's as though the world
finally comes into focus.
Everything I've learned...
is helping point me
toward the answer.
Learning
how to do new things...
It feels...
So incredible.
I found you.
This is Tranquileaf, all right.
Now, the only thing left to do--
[DOCTOR] Young man!
What do you think
you're doing in there?
[TARTAH] Uh...
[DOCTOR]
You thought everyone was gone?
What a ridiculous idea.
We would never leave
the hospital entirely abandoned.
And there is a reason
those bottles aren't labeled.
It's so people don't fiddle
with them.
You could have caused a problem
far more dangerous
than the one
you were trying to solve.
[TARTAH] I'm sorry.
I suppose I panicked.
[doctor sighs]
It's a good impulse
to want to take care
of your friend.
But medicines
can also be poison.
It takes knowledge
and experience
to use them correctly.
That said, in this case,
Tranquileaf is exactly
what was called for.
Do you know very much
about medicine?
Interested in becoming a doctor?
[TARTAH]
Oh. Well, actually...
Oh, I see, that hat.
I didn't realize I was
addressing an apprentice witch.
[Tartah breathes softly]
[DOCTOR] We managed
to get all the injured out.
[WITCH 1] Well done, everyone.
[QIFREY]
Thank you for your support.
Seems the fire is mostly out.
Mind if I leave things
in your hands from here?
My apprentice is rather--
Where do you think you're going?
We're not done here!
There's still a huge mess
at the site to clean up!
This sort of thing's easy
for you witch types, right?
Just wiggle your fingers
and problem solved!
You have to lead the way
at times like these,
use your powers for good!
We're all counting on you, son!
Ah, sir? I'm afraid that's
a bit of an oversimplification.
Outsiders don't understand
these things.
[Qifrey sighs]
You may go on
and take your leave.
This is under control.
[QIFREY] My thanks again.
[QIFREY]
Things are easy for witches.
Hardly.
If they were,
we wouldn't have
to worry or suffer as we do.
[Qifrey exhales softly]
[bird squawking]
[grunts]
I can breathe so easily!
Good to hear.
Apparently, the medicine worked.
Thanks for your help, Tartah!
[TARTAH] Well...
Honestly, I'd say
you're the one who helped me.
[Coco sighs softly]
[Tartah chuckles]
Witches really are amazing.
[Coco chuckles]
You know, I couldn't agree more.
[bell tolling]
[NOLNOA] Staying out all night.
You worried me half to death.
[TARTAH] Sorry, Granda.
I do appreciate you
keeping me apprised, Qifrey.
Of course. You'd do the same
if the roles were reversed.
[TARTAH] Oh, that's right.
My question.
I wanted to ask about
that unusual flash of light
that appeared the other day.
[BOTH] Flash of light?
[TARTAH] Hm?
Actually, never mind.
You push yourself
entirely too hard, you know.
Don't endanger your health now.
Thank you, my friend.
[TARTAH] I suppose
it's possible I imagined it.
Well, whether I did or I didn't,
I'll have to look into it
on my own.
[NOLNOA] Tartah.
The ferry's leaving.
[TARTAH] Uh...
[COCO] Master! I'm sorry
to have kept you waiting.
[FERRYMAN] Boat's heading out.
- [COCO] Tartah!
- [TARTAH] Huh?
[COCO] See you soon!
[QIFREY] Right then.
Let's head home.
[COCO] Let's!
- [TARTAH] Coco!
- [COCO] Huh?
[TARTAH] Listen, I'm going
to carve a pen for you!
And then, I'll cross this river
using my own magic.
And deliver it to you
personally! I promise!
[Coco exclaims, chuckles]
I can't wait to see
what it looks like!
[Tartah chuckles]
[NOLNOA] Well, now, you two have
grown rather close,
- have you?
- [TARTAH] Hm.
She's amazing.
Still, though.
Not as amazing
as she's going to become.
Huh?
My dear boy.
I suspect you'll be
amazing, too.
[Tartah gasps softly]
[Tartah chuckles]
♪
[QIFREY] Poor girl.
You've been tormented
by nightmares all this time?
Dreams are difficult
to deal with.
Sleeping spells
are forbidden, after all.
Still, I'm sure we can find
some way to help.
Necessity is the mother
of invention, as they say.
[COCO] That's very kind.
But you know,
I think I'll be all right now.
[QIFREY] Are you sure?
[COCO] Yes, I am.
Because I discovered
a ray of hope.
Inverting the signs
when you draw them
reverses their effect.
Surely, forbidden spells
work the same way!
If I draw inverse signs
of the seal in that book,
maybe I can reverse the spell
that turned my mom to stone!
[TETIA] Coco!
Hej med dig!
I've been so worried!
Is your fever all gone?
- [COCO] Yes.
- Hurrah!
Thank goodness! I'm so glad!
[Agott sighs]
[SASARAN] Your gift
didn't work out terribly well,
now did it?
The days of peace
have not yet made fools
of all the Pointed Caps.
We can't sit idle.
It seems further action
is called for.
[IGUIN] I see. So then, you...
the embodiment
of forbidden magic...
will take that action?
[SASARAN]
That's my intention.
During a test,
an apprentice must leave
their master's protection.
That is when we must strike.
EPISODE 11:
THE TEST IN SERPENTBACK CAVE